{"tossups": [{"question": "This man shared power with Nikolai Podgorny and Alexander Kosygin in the early years of his leadership, and his poor economic planning led to the beginning of the Era of Stagnation. This leader joined Jimmy Carter in signing the SALT II accords. He justified military intervention to protect communism in a namesake doctrine. For ten points, name this Soviet General Secretary who succeeded Nikita Khrushchev.", "answer": "Leonid<b> Brezhnev</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This country\u2019s Catatumbo River has more lightning than anywhere else on Earth. A brackish inlet in this country was home to a 1914 oil discovery and an 1823 naval battle that earned this country\u2019s independence from Spain. This country is home to the tallest waterfall in the world, Angel Falls, and the mouth of the Orinoco River. Lake Maracaibo is found in, for ten points, what South American country where a \u201cBolivarian Revolution\u201d was led by Hugo Chavez?", "answer": "Bolivarian Republic of<b> Venezuela</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "A theme in Mozart\u2019s twenty-fifth piano concerto is sometimes cited as this song\u2019s source. Pyotr Lavrov wrote a \u201cworker\u2019s\u201d version of this song, which was originally written by Claude Rouget de Lisle as \u201cWar Song for the Rhine Army.\u201d A musical depiction of the Battle of Borodino juxtaposes this song with \u201cGod Save The Tsar.\u201d This song was quoted in Tchaikovsky\u2019s<em> 1812 Overture</em>, where it represents Napoleon\u2019s army. For ten points, name this revolutionary song, the national anthem of France.", "answer": "La<b> Marseillaise</b> [mar-say-ehz]", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "This organization was criticized for being unable to control the Orange Riots. Charles Murphy tried to reform this organization, which supported Al Smith for President in 1928. Jimmy Hines was unable to stop this organization\u2019s defeat by Fiorello LaGuardia. A leader of this organization was targeted by Samuel Tilden and depicted with a bag of money for a head by Thomas Nast. For ten points, name this Democratic political machine in New York City that was dominated by Boss Tweed.", "answer": "<b> Tammany</b> Hall (or the Society of St.<b> Tammany</b> or the Sons of St.<b> Tammany</b> or the <b>Columbian</b> Order) Page 1", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "After rising to power, this group banned the practice of \u201cBacha Bazi\u201d between Pashtun warlords. Some former supporters of this group have defected to ISIs\u2019s Khorasan Province branch. In March 2001, this group demolished giant, centuries-old statues of the Buddha in Bamiyan Province; later in 2001, this group was ousted from power by a NATO-led coalition. For ten points, name this Sunni terrorist group that operates in Afghanistan.", "answer": "<b> Taliban</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "An early action during this conflict was the capture of Government House in Stanley. This conflict began on the orders of Leopoldo Galtieri, who lost power as a result. During this war, Exocet missiles were able to destroy the<em> Sheffield</em>, and the<em> Conqueror</em> was able to sink the<em> General Belgrano</em>. This war\u2019s outcome hastened the fall of a military junta while strengthening Margaret Thatcher\u2019s government. For ten points, name this 1982 war between Argentina and Britain over a South Atlantic archipelago.", "answer": "<b> Falkland</b>s War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Two answers required. During an election contested between these two men, the endorsement of John Crittenden swung the election to the winner. A speech by one of these men was used to begin the other\u2019s Cooper Union speech, given to elaborate his views by invoking the Founding Fathers. One of these men issued the Freeport Doctrine, articulating his support for popular sovereignty, during a series of senatorial debates between these two men in 1858. For ten points, name these two Illinois politicians, who finished first and fourth in the Presidential election of 1860.", "answer": "Abraham<b> Lincoln</b> and Stephen<b> Douglas</b> (accept in either order; accept<b> Lincoln-Douglas </b>debates or similar)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s reputation suffered when two dozen miners were killed in a firefight at his Ludlow colony. Charles Pratt and Henry Rogers decided to work with this man after their companies were priced out in the \u201cCleveland Massacre.\u201d When this man\u2019s monopoly was found to be in violation of the Sherman Antitrust Act, it was split into companies that became Exxon and Mobil. For ten points, name this wealthiest American of all time, the founder of the Standard Oil Company.", "answer": "John D.<b> Rockefeller</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This leader called a Congress of Berlin in order to override the Treaty of San Stefano. He supported Lord Derby\u2019s attempts to pass a Reform Act prohibiting rotten boroughs. This leader\u2019s foreign policies included buying out the Suez Canal Company and ordering a failed invasion of Afghanistan as part of the Great Game with Russia. This politician was a favorite of Queen Victoria and crowned her Empress of India. For ten points, name this Conservative prime minister of Great Britain and rival of William Gladstone.", "answer": "Benjamin<b> Disraeli</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "The monarchy in this region was replaced by a republic after the Anif declaration. This region was united with the Palatinate by Charles Theodore and acquired new territory after the Treaty of Pressburg with Napoleon. A duchy in this region was ruled by the Wittelsbachs and led the Counter-Reformation as a bastion of Catholicism. Its \u201cMad King,\u201d Ludwig II, built Neuschwanstein [noysh-van-stein] castle in this region and allied with Austria against Prussia. For ten points, name this southern region of Germany, governed from Munich.", "answer": "<b> Bavaria</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "An invasion of this country began shortly after Robert Paz was shot on his way to dinner in the El Chorrillo [chore-ee-oh] neighborhood. Loud rock music was used to flush a leader of this country out of the Vatican embassy, where he had taken refuge. In an attempt to stop drug trafficking in this country, George H.W. Bush authorized military intervention in Operation Just Cause in 1989. For ten points, name this Central American country from which Manuel Noriega was removed from power.", "answer": "<b> Panama</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This work claims that religion is necessary to support political prosperity and notes that\u201cthe jealousy of a free people ought to be constantly awake\u201d against the \u201cinsidious wiles of foreign influence.\u201d This work draws an analogy between the interdependence of the (+) north to south and east to west, arguing that decisions must be made as one nation. This speech cautions against the influence of European foreign powers and of the dangers of (*) </b>political parties. For ten points, name this work, which was published rather than delivered as a speech, near the end of the first U.S. president\u2019s term.", "answer": "George<b> Washington\u2019s Farewell Address</b> (accept descriptive answers; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Other Social Science"}, {"question": "<b>Two answers required. The fleets of these two nations joined up to defeat Andrea Doria</b> <b>at Ponza. Fears of Habsburg expansion after Charles V\u2019s capture of Tunis led (+)</b> <b>Jean de</b> <b>la Forest to negotiate a military treaty between these two nations. These two nations faced each other in the Battle of the Pyramids during the Egyptian campaign, which marked the end of the 1536 (*)</b> \u201cUnholy Alliance\u201d signed by Francis I and Suleiman the Magnificent. For ten points, name these two European empires, led by Napoleon and Sultan Selim III.", "answer": "<b> France and</b> the<b> Ottoman</b> Empire", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>James Frazer used the post-hoc fallacy to explain the development of this concept in early culture. Marcel Mauss and Henri Hubert developed a sociological theory of this</b> <b>phenomenon which claimed that it was the \u201cprivate\u201d manifestation of (+)</b> <b>religion. Ralph</b> <b>Merrifield first defined this concept in anthropology as the use of practices intended to harness the occult. This concept was described in (*)</b> \u201cCoral Gardens\u201d in a Bronislaw Malinowski work about these beliefs in the Trobriand Islands. For ten points, name this idea that rituals, actions, and symbols can be used to exploit the supernatural, supposedly performed by wizards.", "answer": "<b> magic</b> (broadly accept similar answers, like<b> wizardry</b>,<b> sorcery</b>, casting<b> spells</b>, etc.) Page 9", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Anthropology"}, {"question": "<b>For his efforts during an attempt at this action, Michel Ney was dubbed the \u201cbravest of the brave.\u201d The truce of Deulino ended a successful instance of this action, which included</b> <b>the Battle of (+)</b> <b>Klushino. A leader fled to the Ottoman Empire after the Great Frost of</b> <b>1709 doomed an attempt at this action, which ended with a defeat for Adam Leuwenhaupt. A failed attempt at this action was doomed by scorched earth tactics, (*) </b> Cossacks, and\u201cGeneral Winter.\u201d For ten points, name this difficult military action that Napoleon attempted in 1812.", "answer": "<b> invading Russia</b> (accept elaborations involving French, Polish, and/or Swedish<b> invasions of Russia</b>) (6) <b>Olefin polymerization can be catalyzed by compounds containing this metal that are</b> <b>named for Ziegler and Natta. In 1888, Karl Josef Bayer developed a process for refining</b> <b>the oxide of this element from (+)</b> <b>bauxite; the smelting of this element is then typically</b> <b>done through the electrolytic Hall-H\u00b4eroult process. This element is the most common metal found in the Earth\u2019s (*) </b> crust and is crucial for aerospace technology. For ten points, name this lightweight metal with atomic number 13 that is used in soda cans. ANSWER:<b> aluminum</b> (accept<b> Al</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The Revolt of the Lankans took place in this colony among angry nobles called</b><em><b> datus</b></em><b>, who were divided into the Puno, Ginoo, and Maginoo. This colony was founded after the conquest of the Moro people and conflicts with (+) Brunei and Sulu. Ships departing from this colony brought porcelain and china to Acapulco across the Pacific. The discoverer of this colony, (*)</b> Ferdinand Magellan, died here during the Battle of Mactan. For ten points, name this Spanish colony where galleons brought silver to the port of Manila.", "answer": "<b> Philippines</b> (or the<b> Spanish East Indies</b>) Page 10", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}